接下来的这段视频是关于推断的
This next video is on inferring
我喜欢把这些任务看成是模型将一个文本作为输入并进行某种分析
I like to think of these tasks where the model takes
作为输入的文本并进行某种分析
a text as input and perform some kind of analysis
所以这可能是提取标签
So this could be extracting labels
提取名字，理解文本的情感，诸如此类的事情
extracting names, kind of understanding the sentiment of a text, that kind of thing
因此，如果你想提取一个情感
So if you want to extract a sentiment
正面或负面的文本
positive or negative of a piece of text
在传统的机器学习工作流程中
in the traditional machine learning workflow
你必须要收集标签数据集
you'd have to collect the label dataset
训练一个模型，弄清楚如何在云端的某个地方部署这个模型
train a model, figure out how to deploy the model somewhere in the Cloud
并做出推断
and make inferences
这可以很好地工作
That can work pretty well
但要经历这个过程，实在是一件很费力的事情
but it was just a lot of work to go through that process
此外，对于每一项任务，如情感分析与提取名字或其他东西
Also, for every task such as sentiment versus extracting names versus something else
你必须训练和部署一个单独的模型
you have to train and deploy a separate model
关于大语言模型的一个好处是
One of the really nice things about
对于许多像这样的任务
large language model is that for many tasks like these
你可以只写一个提示，然后让它马上开始生成结果
you can just write a prompt and have it start generating results pretty much right away
这给应用程序的开发带来了巨大的提速
That gives tremendous speed in terms of application development
你也可以只使用一个模型
You can also just use one model
一个API来完成许多不同的任务，而不需要
one API to do many different tasks rather than needing to
弄清楚如何训练和部署许多不同的模型
figure out how to train and deploy a lot of different models
有了这些，让我们跳进代码，看看你如何利用这个优势
With that, let's jump into the code to see how you can take advantage of this
这里是我们通常的初始代码
Here's our usual starter code
运行这个
I'll just run that
我使用的最多的例子，是关于一盏灯的评论
The most of the example I'm going to use is a review for a lamp
卧室里需要一盏漂亮的灯
Need a nice lamp for the bedroom
和额外存储空间的家具，等等
and this one additional storage, and so on
让我写一个提示，对这个的情绪进行分类
Let me write a prompt to classify the sentiment of this
如果我想让系统告诉我这是什么情绪
If I want the system to tell me what is the sentiment
我可以直接写出 "以下产品评论的情感是什么"
I can just write what is the sentiment of the following product review
加上通常的分隔符和评论文本等等，然后让我们运行这个提示
with the usual delimiter and the review text and so on, and let's run that
这表示该产品评论的情绪是积极的
This says the sentiment of the product review is positive
这实际上似乎很正确
which actually seems pretty right
这盏灯并不完美，但这位顾客看起来很满意
This lamp isn't perfect, but this customer seems pretty happy
这似乎是一个关心客户和产品的伟大公司
Seems to be a great company that cares about the customers and products
我认为积极的情绪似乎是正确的答案
I think positive sentiment seems to be the right answer
现在，这就把整个句子打印出来
Now, this prints out the entire sentence
该产品评论的情绪是积极的
the sentiment of the product review is positive
如果你想给出一个更简洁的回答，以便于后期处理
If you wanted to give a more concise response to make it easier for post-processing
我可以在这个提示中加入另一条指令
I can take this prompt and add another instruction
只给你一个单词的答案
to give you answers to single word
正面或负面
either positive or negative
它只是像这样打印出正面，这对一段文字来说更容易
It just prints out positive like this, which makes it easier for a piece of text
来处理这个输出，并对它做一些处理
to take this output and process it and do something with it
让我们看一下另一个提示
Let's look at another prompt
再来一遍，仍然使用关于台灯的评论
Again, still using the lamp review
在这里，我让它识别一个列表
Here, I have it identify a list of
以下评论的作者所表达的情绪
emotions that the writer of the following review is expressing
在这个列表中包括不超过五个项目
including no more than five items in this list
大语言模型在以下方面相当出色
Large language models are pretty good at
从一段文本中提取特定的东西
extracting specific things out of a piece of text
在这种情况下，我们要表达的是情绪
In this case, we're expressing the emotions
这对于了解
This could be useful for understanding how
你的客户对某一特定产品的看法
your customers think about a particular product
对于很多客户支持机构来说，了解客户对产品的看法很重要
For a lot of customer support organizations
理解一个特定的用户是否对你的产品非常不满是非常重要的
it's important to understand if a particular user is extremely upset
你可能有这样一个不同的分类问题
You might have a different classification problem like this
下面这篇评论的作者是否在表达愤怒？
is the writer of the following review expressing anger?
因为如果某人真的很生气
Because if someone is really angry
它可能值得付出额外的关注来获得客户评论
it might merit paying extra attention to have a customer review
获得客户支持或成功拿下客户
to have customer support or customer success
伸出援手，弄清楚发生了什么事，并为客户把事情做好
reach out to figure what's going on and make things right for the customer
在这种情况下，客户并不生气
In this case, the customer is not angry
注意，有了监督学习
Notice that with supervised learning
如果我想建立所有这些分类器
if I had wanted to build all of these classifiers
我不可能用监督学习在短短几分钟内完成这些工作
there's no way I would have been able to do this with
而你在这段视频中看到我这样做了
supervised learning in just a few minutes that you saw me do so in this video
我鼓励你暂停这个视频，并尝试改变其中的一些提示
I'd encourage you to pause this video and try changing some of these prompts
也许问一下客户是否表达了喜悦之情，或者问一下是否有
Maybe ask if the customer is expressing delight or ask if there are
任何缺失的部分，看看你是否能得到一个提示来
any missing parts and see if you can get a prompt to
对这个实验室进行不同的推断
make different inferences about this lab review
让我再展示一下你可以用这个系统做的一些事情
Let me show some more things that you can do with this system
特别是从客户评论中提取更丰富的信息
specifically extracting richer information from a customer review
信息提取是NLP的一部分
Information extraction is the part of NLP
自然语言处理的一部分，它涉及到将一段文本
of natural language processing that relates to taking a piece of
并从文本中提取出你想知道的某些东西
text and extracting certain things that you want to know from the text
在这个提示中，我问它
In this prompt, I'm asking it
确定以下项目
identify the following items
购买的物品和制造该物品的公司名称
the item purchase and the name of the company that made the item
同样，如果你想从一个在线购物的电子商务网站上总结出许多评论
Again, if you are trying to summarize many reviews from an online shopping e-commerce website
对于你收集的大量评论来说
it might be useful for your large collection of
弄清楚这些评论所涉及的物品可能会很有用
reviews to figure out what were the items
可以通过分析评论中的内容，找出评论涉及的物品制造商
who made the item, figure out positive and negative sentiment
并确定积极和消极情绪
to track trends about positive or negative sentiment for
以追踪特定物品或制造商的积极或消极情绪趋势
specific items or for specific manufacturers
在这个例子中，我将要求它把响应格式化为
In this example, I'm going to ask it to format your response as
一个以项目和品牌为键的JSON对象
a JSON object with item and brand as the keys
如果我这样做了，它就会说这个物品是一盏灯
If I do that, it says the item is a lamp
品牌是Luminar
the brand is Luminar
你可以很容易地将其加载到
and you can easily load this into
Python字典中，然后对这个输出做额外的处理
Python dictionary to then do additional processing on this output
在我们所经历的例子中
In the examples we've gone through
你看到了如何写一个提示来识别情感
you saw how to write a prompt to recognize the sentiment
弄清某人是否生气
figure out if someone is angry
然后再提取物品和品牌
and then also extract the item and the brand
提取所有这些信息的一个方法是使用三或四个提示语
One way to extract all of this information would be to use three or four prompts
并调用三次或四次get_completion
and call get_completion three times or four times
一次一次地提取这些不同的字段
extract these different fields one at a time
但事实证明，你实际上可以只写一个提示符
But it turns out you can actually write a single prompt
来同时提取所有这些信息
to extract all of this information at the same time
比方说识别以下项目
Let's say identify the following items
提取情绪，是评论者表达愤怒
extract sentiment, is a reviewer expressing anger
项目的购买，公司的动画
item purchase, company animated
然后在这里，我还要告诉它把愤怒值格式化为一个布尔值
Then here, I'm also going to tell it to format the anger value as a Boolean value
让我运行它
Let me run that
这将输出一个JSON，其中情绪是积极的
This outputs a JSON where sentiment is positive
愤怒，然后在false周围没有引号
anger, and then no quotes around false
因为它也只是把它输出为一个布尔值
because it also just output it as a Boolean value
提取出"lamp with additional storage"作为物品，而不仅仅是"lamp"
Extracted the item as lamp with additional storage instead of lamp
看起来还不错
Seems okay
这种方法让你只需一个提示
But this way, you can extract multiple fields out of
就可以从一段文本中提取多个字段
a piece of text with just a single prompt
像往常一样，请随意暂停视频
As usual, please feel free to pause the video
并在此基础上试玩一下，感受不同变化
and play with different variations on this yourself
或者甚至可以尝试输入一个完全不同的评论，看看你是否
Or maybe even try typing in a totally different review to see if you
能否仍然准确地提取这些东西
can still extract these things accurately
现在，我看到大型语言模型很酷的应用之一
Now, one of the cool applications I've seen of
是推断主题
large language models is inferring topics
给出一段长的文字
Given a long piece of text
这段文字是关于什么的？
what is this piece of text about?
主题是什么？
What are the topics?
这是一篇虚构的报纸文章，关于如何
Here's a fictitious newspaper article about how
政府工作人员对他们所工作的机构的感受
government workers feel about the agency they work for
最近由政府等进行的调查
The recent survey conducted by government and so on
结果审查，NASA是
results reviewed at NASA was
一个受欢迎的部门，满意度很高
a popular department with high satisfaction rating
我是NASA的粉丝
I am a fan of NASA
喜欢他们所做的工作，但这是一篇虚构的文章
love the work they do, but this is a fictitious article
鉴于这样的文章
Given an article like this
我们可以用这个提示来问它
we can ask it with this prompt
确定以下文本中讨论的五个主题
determine five topics that are being discussed in the following text
让我们把每一项都写成一到两个字的长度
Let's make each item one or two words long
为我的回答，用逗号分隔的列表
for my response, comma separated list
如果我们运行这个
If we run that
我们就会发现，这篇文章是关于政府调查的
we get out this article is about a government survey
是关于工作满意度的，是关于NASA的，等等
is about job satisfaction, is about NASA, and so on
总的来说，我认为相当不错的主题列表的提取
Overall, I think pretty nice extraction of a list of topics
当然，你也可以把它分开，这样你就可以得到
Of course, you can also split it so you get
一个包含这篇文章所涉及的五个主题的Python列表
a Python list with the five topics that this article was about
如果你有一个文章的集合，并提取主题
If you have a collection of articles and extract topics
那么你还可以使用
you can then also use
一个大语言模型来帮助你索引到不同的主题
a large language model to help you index into different topics
让我用一个稍微不同的主题列表
Let me use a slightly different topic list
比方说，我们是一个新闻网站或其他什么
Let's say that we're a news websites or something
而这些是我们追踪的主题
and these are the topics we track
NASA，当地政府，工程
NASA, local government, engineering
员工满意度，联邦政府
employee satisfaction, federal government
比方说，你想弄清楚
Let's say you want to figure out
给出一篇新闻文章
given a news article
这篇新闻报道中涉及哪些主题
which of these topics are covered in that news article
这里有一个提示，我可以使用
Here's a prompt that I can use
我想说的是，确定 "有趣的主题清单 "中的每一项
I'm going to say, determine whether each item in
是否是下面文本中的一个主题
the fun list of topics is a topic in the text below
给出你的答案，这是每个话题的01
Give your answers and this is 01 for each topic
很好。这是和之前一样的故事文本
Great. This is the same story text as before
这个东西是一个故事。它是关于NASA的
This thing is a story. It is about NASA
这不是关于地方政府，不是关于工程
It's not about local governments, not about engineering
它是关于员工满意度的，它是关于联邦政府的
It is about employee satisfaction and it is about federal government
有了这个，在机器学习中
With this, in machine learning
这有时被称为 "零示例学习算法"
this is sometimes called a zero-shot learning algorithm
因为我们没有给它任何有标签的训练数据
because we didn't give it any training data that was labeled
这就是零示例
That's zero-shot
只需一个提示
With just a prompt
它就能够确定哪些
it was able to determine which of
这些主题在那篇新闻报道中被涵盖
these topics are covered in that news article
如果你想生成一个新闻警报
If you want to generate a news alert
这样处理新闻，我真的很喜欢NASA做的很多工作
so that process news and I really like a lot of work that NASA does
如果你想建立一个系统，可以把这个
If you want to build a system that can take this
把这些信息放到一个字典里，每当
put this information into a dictionary and whenever
NASA的新闻出现，就打印提醒
NASA news pops up, print alert
新的NASA故事，他们可以用这个来非常迅速地采取任何文章
new NASA story, they can use this to very quickly take any article
弄清楚它是关于什么主题的
figure out what topics it is about
如果该主题包括NASA
and if the topic includes NASA
让它打印出警报，新的NASA故事
have it print out alert, new NASA story
只有一件事，我在下面使用这个主题词典
Just one thing, I use this topic dictionary down here
我在上面使用的这个提示不是很强大
This prompt that I use up here isn't very robust
如果我想要一个生产系统
If I wanted a production system
我可能会让它以JSON格式输出答案
I would probably have it output the answer in JSON format
而不是作为一个列表，因为输出的
rather than as a list because the output
大语言模型会有一点不一致
of the large language model can be a little bit inconsistent
这实际上是一段很脆弱 的代码
This is actually a pretty brittle piece of code
但是，如果你想，当你看完这个视频后
But if you want, when you're done watching this video
可以看看你能不能想出办法来修改这个提示
feel free to see if you can figure out how to modify this prompt
让它输出JSON而不是像这样的一个列表
to have it output JSON instead of a list like this
然后有一个更强大的方法来判断某篇文章是否是关于NASA的故事
and then have a more robust way to tell if a particular article is a story about NASA
所以，这就是推断的内容
So that's it for inferring
在短短的几分钟内
In just a few minutes
你可以建立多个系统，对文本进行推断
you can build multiple systems for making inferences about
这些推断以前需要一名熟练的机器学习开发人员
text that previously just would have taken days or
花费数天甚至数周才能完成
even weeks for a skilled machine learning developer
我认为，无论是对于熟练的机器学习开发人员
I find this very exciting that both for
还是机器学习新手而言
skilled machine learning developers as well as for
这都是非常令人兴奋的消息
people that are newer to machine learning
你现在可以使用提示来非常快速地建立并开始
you can now use prompting to very quickly build and start
对这些相当复杂的自然语言处理任务做出推断
making inferences on pretty complicated natural language processing tasks like these
在下一个视频中
In the next video
我们将继续讨论令人激动的事情，你可以用
we'll continue to talk about exciting things you could do with
大语言模型，我们将继续进行转换
large language models and we'll go on to transforming
把一段文本转换为
How can you take one piece of text and transform it into
不同的文本，如翻译成不同的语言
a different piece of text such as translated to a different language
让我们继续看下一个视频
Let's go on to the next video